how many valence electrons do each of
the following atoms have to find the
number of valence electrons for these
representative elements all we have to
do is look at their group number valence
electrons are the electrons in the
highest occupied energy level of an
element's atom the periodic table is
organized to tell us the valence
electrons according to the group numbers
for the representative elements so all
we have to do is look at the group
number and that's the number of valence
electrons calcium CA has two valence
electrons because it's in group two
nitrogen n has five and Xenon XE has
eight thanks for watching if this video
helped you out please give it a like And
subscribe to the channel